KAREN ASTELL

Londonderry, NH 03053 ◆ (603) 770-7658 ◆ karenastell@gmail.com

https://github.com/karenastell/ ◆ https://karenastell.github.io/portfolio/index.html

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

My name is Karen Astell and I am extremely excited to begin my journey into full-stack web development. I've earned a Bachelor of Science in Math Education and a Masters of Education, both from the University of New Hampshire. The decision making and collaborative skills I've acquired over the past 15 years in education will help me tremendously in the world of web development. I am decisive yet adaptable in high-pressure environments and have a real passion for collaborating with others. I have completed a full-stack web development certification program through UNH's Coding Bootcamp. During this course, I developed my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Node.js as well as focusing on creating responsive web applications. Employers often acknowledge my problem-solving skills and a strong work ethic which lends itself to working in web development teams or individual projects. I am eager to create web applications that are applicable and user friendly. I look forward to beginning my new career in web development.

SKILLS

- Team building
- Web development
- Troubleshooting
- Project Management
- Programming Languages
- Team oversight
- Communication
- Group and individual instruction

- Conflict resolution techniques
- Team management
- Relationship development
- Problem resolution
- Student records management
- Student counseling
- Student progress reporting
- Differentiated instruction

WORK HISTORY

Behavior Specialist, 07/2009 to 06/2020

Merrimack School District - Merrimack, NH

- Partnered with administrative leadership to improve discipline practices based on data findings.
- Conducted weekly groups to support students in developing social-emotional and behavioral skills.
- Cultivated connections and strong student rapport to foster classroom engagement, in addition to recording student progress to inform parents and school administration.

- Led activities that developed students' physical, emotional, and social growth.
- Communicated nonverbally with children to provide comfort, encouragement, and positive reinforcement.
- Resolved conflicts and negotiated mutually beneficial agreements between parties.

Residential Counselor, 06/2007 to 08/2018

Nashua Children's Home - Nashua, NH

- Utilized CPI-NCI intervention techniques to deescalate aggressive and hostile behavior of residents.
- Attended weekly meetings to develop and implement individually tailored treatment plans to lead residents to successful reintegration into society.
- Resolved conflicts by performing in-time crisis intervention and enforcing discipline and behavior expectations.
- Addressed behavioral and emotional needs of residents through activities and interventions, increasing resident socialization, interpersonal and social skills.

Teacher, 07/2005 to 06/2007

Timberlane School District - Atkinson, NH

- Kept students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Reviewed curriculum and devised alternate approaches to presenting lessons to increase student understanding.
- Enhanced student learning by optimizing a wide range of instructional approaches and innovative classroom activities.
- Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to facilitate and moderate classroom discussions and student-centered learning.
- Held conferences with parents to address questions, discuss academic progress, and encourage learning goals.
- Promoted and modeled a lifelong love of learning and reading.

EDUCATION

Certificate: Coding Bootcamp, Expected in 09/2020

University of New Hampshire - Durham, NH

Bachelor of Science: Math Education, 05/2004 **University of New Hampshire** - Durham, NH

Master of Education: Elementary Education, 05/2005

University of New Hampshire - Durham, NH